Guide to the Irwin Silver Photograph Collection 1977-2002 PR 209
© 2011 New-York Historical Society
Irwin Silver Photograph Collection
1977-2002
PR 209
© 2011 New-York Historical Society
2.26 Linear feet (2 boxes)
The Irwin Silver Photograph Collection contains photographs of New York City, primarily of memorial activities after the September 11, 2001, collapse of the World Trade Center towers.
Provenance
Gift of Irwin Silver, 1994 and 2003.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers.
Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to thirty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. See guidelines in Print Room for details.
Scope and Content Note
The Irwin Silver Photograph Collection spans the period from 1977-2002 and contains photographs of New York City, primarily of memorial activities after the September 11, 2001 collapse of the World Trade Center towers. The photograph titles were assigned by the photographer.
Arrangement
The collection is divided into two series: New York City September 11 Memorials; and General Photographs.
Related Material at the Department of Prints, Photographs, and Architectural Collections
Other photographs of the World Trade Center and the aftermath of its destruction can be found in PR 169, the World Trade Center Photograph Collection.
Fire fighters; Memorials; New York (N.Y.) -- Buildings, structures, etc.; Photographic prints; September 11 Terrorist Attacks, 2001; Streets -- New York (State) -- New York
- Series I: New York City September 11 Memorials
  Scope and Contents note
  Series I contains eighteen images from the photographer's series of the same name. The photographs are all black and white, 11x14 prints, and show memorials for people who died during the World Trade Center collapse. Many show public and private memorials to firefighters. Others show more public memorials, such as a fence where memorial tiles were hung. All the photographs were taken in 2002.
  Prints are arranged chronologically by month.
  - Memorial sheet, St. Paul's Chapel Gate, 2002 Jan. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Nereida De Jesus, memorial wall, St. Paul's Church, 2002 Jan. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Snowman and memorial wall, St. Paul's Chapel Gate, 2002 Jan. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Memorial wall, St. Paul's Chapel Gate, 2002 Jan. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Family on Church and Park Place on "viewing platform" line, 2002 Jan. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Rescue 1, NYFD, Memorial, 2002 Mar. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Transit Police District Four, NYPD, Memorial, Union Square Subway Station, 2002 Mar. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Children's art, Victim's Assistance Center, 51 Chambers Street, 2002 Mar. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Firefighter Reuben David Correa, Engine 74, W. 83rd Street, 2002 Mar. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Engine Company 3, Ladder Company 12, 7th Battalion, NYFD, Memorial, 2002 Mar. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Art Aid memorial with portrait of Captain Patrick J. Brown, Union Square Subway Station, 2002 May (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Art Aid memorial with portrait of James Francis Quinn, Union Square Subway Station, 2002 May (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Court Officer's Memorial, New York State Supreme Court, 111 Centre Street, 2002 May (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Tiles on fence, Greenwich House Project, 7th Avenue and Greenwich Avenue, 2002 May (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Tiles on fence (long shot), Greenwich House Project, 7th Avenue and Greenwich Avenue, 2002 May (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Interior, Rescue 2, 2002 May (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Fire Engine Door (salvaged from World Trade Center) memorial, Rescue 2, NYFD, 2002 May (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - African-American Firefighters Memorial, Vulcan Hall, Eastern Parkway and Kingston Avenue, Brooklyn, 2002 Sep. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Series II: General Photographs
  Series II contains three photographs of New York City, which date from 1977 to 2002. Two black and white images from 1977 and 1990 show New York street scenes from the Lower East Side. A color chromogenic type C print, taken in 2002, shows a replica of the Statue of Liberty being transported from the roof of the Liberty Storage Warehouse on West 64th Street to the Brooklyn Museum of Art.
  - Replica of Statue of Liberty, 2002 Feb. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Hanover Street, NYC, Autumn 1977 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Orchard Street New York City, June 5, 1990, 1990, Jun. 5 (Box 2, Folder 6)